<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My LEGO Blog</title>
    <description>A personal blog for a journey in LEGO</description>
    <link>https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 10:32:29 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 10:32:29 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Basics</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is about a few ideas and observations since I started LEGO hobby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LEGO is so versatile that there is not a single recipe to get started. Here’s a list of what I observed people do with their LEGO hobbies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;builder-path&quot;&gt;Builder path&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build official LEGO sets: LEGO has so many sets available it’s almost impossible to get all of them (It would cost a fortune too!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/09/24/basics/IMG_2463.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;LEGO Harley Davidson&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build MOCs: Most fun path IMHO! Just use your own imagination, creativity and skills and build your own models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;collector-path&quot;&gt;Collector path&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy LEGO sets and other collectibles (promotional items, keyrings etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/09/24/basics/IMG_3003.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;My LEGO keyring collection&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/09/24/basics/IMG_3248.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;My sealed LEGO sets&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;investor-path&quot;&gt;Investor path&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy and sell LEGO sets.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy and part out sets and sell the parts/minifigures on BrickLink or BrickOwl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These paths are not mutually exclusive though. It’s very likely a collector might as well start selling some of the items for profit or to buy more LEGO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main goal with this hobby is to build my own MOCs and combine them with lights and electronics to add motion and bring more life to the models I build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to get started is to simply go to LEGO.com and buy some sets. Start small and cheap. Pick a theme that you are interested in (Star Wars, Marvel, DC, Ninjago, Minecraft etc) and pick a set you fancy. After you build it you’ll know if this hobby is for you or not. If not then it’s perfectly fine because you haven’t buried a lot of money. If yes, then you’re about to embark a long and fun journey!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sourcing-the-materials&quot;&gt;Sourcing the materials&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you intend to create your own models it becomes tricky because you now have to buy individual bricks and pieces. There are a few ways of doing this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy some sets on clearance and part them out. “Parting out” means putting all the individual pieces in boxes/bins or whatever storage you’re using without building the actual set. It’s generally cheaper to supply the pieces this way.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy bulk used LEGO: Possibly the cheapest way of obtaining parts. Some people are simply trying to get rid of their child’s old LEGO and don’t care about making a huge profit off of it. That’s where you come in! The biggest downside of bulk used LEGO is you almost always get a whole bunch of non-LEGO in the bulk. It can be some off-brand bricks, crayons, rocks, dirt, hair etc. So it’s a good idea to give them a wash before even touching them. eBay and Facebook marketplace are good places to buy bulk LEGO. Another downside is the amount of time you need to spend on sorting it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/09/24/basics/IMG_2842.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;About 10KG LEGO waiting to be sorted&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy individual parts directly from LEGO marketplaces such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.BrickLink.com&quot;&gt;BrickLink&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.BrickOwl.com&quot;&gt;BrickOwl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy individual parts from LEGO Pick A Brick (In stores or online)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy individual parts from LEGO Bricks and Pieces. It’s mostly meant to replace missing/broken pieces but can be used to order other pieces as well on the cheap side.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is just a few observations and opinions about how to get started and how to expand going forward. Hope it helps to give a broad overview for beginners like me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.BrickLink.com&quot;&gt;BrickLink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.BrickOwl.com&quot;&gt;BrickOwl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lego.com/&quot;&gt;LEGO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/09/24/basics/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/09/24/basics/</guid>
        
        <category>basics</category>
        
        
        <category>info</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting Started</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is going to be my new blog to document my attempt to take up LEGO as a hobby. It doesn’t have a strict direction in mind at the moment. I’ll just post anything LEGO-related and see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 05:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/09/24/getting-started/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/09/24/getting-started/</guid>
        
        <category>introduction</category>
        
        
        <category>misc</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
