<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Volkan's LEGO Blog</title>
    <description>A personal blog for a journey in LEGO</description>
    <link>https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 06:34:15 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 06:34:15 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Set build: Police Helicopter Chase (60243)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I like to small sets as much as I enjoy the larger ones. This one had a nice deal on Argos which is in all honesty the only reason I bought it. I bough 6 and built one of them. I’ll see what I’ll do with the rest in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed the build process though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/09/30/police-helicopter-chase/IMG_3605.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/09/30/police-helicopter-chase/IMG_3606.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/09/30/police-helicopter-chase/IMG_3607.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also I started using the build instruction app rather than the paper booklet that came with the set. I find it a lot more convenient and useful than the paper version as you can rotate and zoom and see the model from all different angles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/09/30/police-helicopter-chase/IMG_0046.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/09/30/police-helicopter-chase/IMG_0047.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lego.com/en-gb/product/police-helicopter-chase-60243&quot;&gt;Police Helicopter Chase set official page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/gb/app/lego-building-instructions/id1486159728&quot;&gt;LEGO instruction app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 04:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/09/30/set-build-police-helicopter-chase-60243/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/09/30/set-build-police-helicopter-chase-60243/</guid>
        
        <category>set</category>
        
        <category>city</category>
        
        <category>police</category>
        
        <category>helicopter</category>
        
        
        <category>build</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Small mod for Sith Troopers Battle Pack</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I like the small sets as they are fun and they are over in a matter of hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/09/27/sith-mod/IMG_3510.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;A few Star Wars battle packs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sith Troopers looks cool (even though I don’t like the sequel movies) in their red uniforms but it would be great if the jet troopers looked like flying as shown on the box:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/09/27/sith-mod/IMG_3599.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Sith Troopers Battle Pack&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I started looking into giving them a flying effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few experimentations this is what I came up with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/09/27/sith-mod/IMG_3602.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Flying Sith jet troopers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/09/27/sith-mod/IMG_3603.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Flying Sith jet troopers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wished they made hinges in trans-clear as well which would make the effect more realistic but I think it’s still good. I didn’t know I had a red plate of that size so that was a happy coincidence as I think it matched the troopers’ armors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I added the build instructions (generated by Studio 2.0) to resources section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is obviously a very simple build. But it was a fun exercise for me to dip my toes into the LEGO ocean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/volkanpaksoy/lego/blob/master/instructions/minigifure-fly-effect.pdf&quot;&gt;Intructions for minifigure fly effect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bricklink.com/v3/studio/download.page&quot;&gt;BrickLink Studio download page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 04:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/09/27/small-mod-for-sith-troopers-battlepack/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/09/27/small-mod-for-sith-troopers-battlepack/</guid>
        
        <category>mod</category>
        
        <category>sw</category>
        
        <category>star_wars</category>
        
        
        <category>moc</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Books</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Books are always a good resource to go over when you’re new to something. I bought a bunch of LEGO-related (well some mostly about LEGO Star Wars) books:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/09/27/books/IMG_3595.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Books&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to learn more about building techniques. Hope these will help with that. More to follow as I read through.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 03:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/09/27/books/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/09/27/books/</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        
        <category>resources</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Inventory</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re going to build MOCs (My Own Creation) then you need to sort your LEGO first. You don’t need an inventory unless you’re planning to sell on BrickLink but you definitely need to keep everything sorted to enjoy this hobby. There are lots of sorting techniques and approaches. The best one is the one that works for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a bit of a control freak so I need to know exactly how many pieces I have in my inventory so after I sorted everything I inventoried them as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/09/26/inventory/IMG_3496.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Personal inventory&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course you need to know what parts are in which locations. To manage that I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://brickstock.patrickbrans.com/&quot;&gt;BrickStock&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a great free and open source software that helps manage your inventory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/09/26/inventory/BrickStock_Screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;BrickStock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an old-school desktop application so make sure to backup your inventories (in .bsx files).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me weeks to identify all the parts. I got a ton of help from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bricklink.com/catalogTree.asp?itemType=P&quot;&gt;BrickLink Part Database&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another major help was learning the part numbers are actually printed on the parts!. Well, most of them at least. This is very useful to weed out non-LEGO parts and also find out what the part is. It’s not very east to read the numbers though. That’s why I bought an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B07XDTRKM8/&quot;&gt;otoscope&lt;/a&gt;. It is essentially a handheld microscope. By the help of this and the part database I was able to find about %99.99 of all the parts I had. So if you have lots of unsorted bulk LEGO I highly recommend buying one of those cameras.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brickstock.patrickbrans.com/&quot;&gt;BrickStock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bricklink.com/catalogTree.asp?itemType=P&quot;&gt;BrickLink Part Database&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B07XDTRKM8/&quot;&gt;Amazon: Otoscope ear camera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 03:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/09/26/inventory/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/09/26/inventory/</guid>
        
        <category>brickstock</category>
        
        <category>inventory</category>
        
        <category>management</category>
        
        
        <category>inventory</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Basics</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is about a few ideas and observations since I started LEGO hobby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LEGO is so versatile that there is not a single recipe to get started. Here’s a list of what I observed people do with their LEGO hobbies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;builder-path&quot;&gt;Builder path&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build official LEGO sets: LEGO has so many sets available it’s almost impossible to get all of them (It would cost a fortune too!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/09/24/basics/IMG_2463.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;LEGO Harley Davidson&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build MOCs: Most fun path IMHO! Just use your own imagination, creativity and skills and build your own models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;collector-path&quot;&gt;Collector path&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy LEGO sets and other collectibles (promotional items, keyrings etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/09/24/basics/IMG_3003.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;My LEGO keyring collection&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/09/24/basics/IMG_3248.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;My sealed LEGO sets&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;investor-path&quot;&gt;Investor path&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy and sell LEGO sets.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy and part out sets and sell the parts/minifigures on BrickLink or BrickOwl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These paths are not mutually exclusive though. It’s very likely a collector might as well start selling some of the items for profit or to buy more LEGO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main goal with this hobby is to build my own MOCs and combine them with lights and electronics to add motion and bring more life to the models I build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to get started is to simply go to LEGO.com and buy some sets. Start small and cheap. Pick a theme that you are interested in (Star Wars, Marvel, DC, Ninjago, Minecraft etc) and pick a set you fancy. After you build it you’ll know if this hobby is for you or not. If not then it’s perfectly fine because you haven’t buried a lot of money. If yes, then you’re about to embark a long and fun journey!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sourcing-the-materials&quot;&gt;Sourcing the materials&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you intend to create your own models it becomes tricky because you now have to buy individual bricks and pieces. There are a few ways of doing this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy some sets on clearance and part them out. “Parting out” means putting all the individual pieces in boxes/bins or whatever storage you’re using without building the actual set. It’s generally cheaper to supply the pieces this way.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy bulk used LEGO: Possibly the cheapest way of obtaining parts. Some people are simply trying to get rid of their child’s old LEGO and don’t care about making a huge profit off of it. That’s where you come in! The biggest downside of bulk used LEGO is you almost always get a whole bunch of non-LEGO in the bulk. It can be some off-brand bricks, crayons, rocks, dirt, hair etc. So it’s a good idea to give them a wash before even touching them. eBay and Facebook marketplace are good places to buy bulk LEGO. Another downside is the amount of time you need to spend on sorting it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/09/24/basics/IMG_2842.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;About 10KG LEGO waiting to be sorted&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy individual parts directly from LEGO marketplaces such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.BrickLink.com&quot;&gt;BrickLink&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.BrickOwl.com&quot;&gt;BrickOwl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy individual parts from LEGO Pick A Brick (In stores or online)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy individual parts from LEGO Bricks and Pieces. It’s mostly meant to replace missing/broken pieces but can be used to order other pieces as well on the cheap side.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is just a few observations and opinions about how to get started and how to expand going forward. Hope it helps to give a broad overview for beginners like me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.BrickLink.com&quot;&gt;BrickLink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.BrickOwl.com&quot;&gt;BrickOwl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lego.com/&quot;&gt;LEGO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/09/24/basics/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/09/24/basics/</guid>
        
        <category>basics</category>
        
        
        <category>info</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting Started</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is going to be my new blog to document my attempt to take up LEGO as a hobby. It doesn’t have a strict direction in mind at the moment. I’ll just post anything LEGO-related and see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 05:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/09/24/getting-started/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/09/24/getting-started/</guid>
        
        <category>introduction</category>
        
        
        <category>misc</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
