<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Volkan's LEGO Blog</title>
    <description>A personal blog for a journey in LEGO</description>
    <link>https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 05:58:07 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 05:58:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Non-LEGO</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Part of buying used Lego in bulk is having to pull out non-LEGO and even non-brick stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/11/28/non-lego/IMG_3735.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a mind of going through all this stuff and try to build because it appears I do have some nice-looking sets (or whatever is left of them):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/11/28/non-lego/IMG_3733.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/11/28/non-lego/IMG_3736.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also came a lot of minifigure and parts some of which yet may be even genuine LEGO:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/11/28/non-lego/IMG_3734.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the time being, I will set them aside but hoping to revisit soon after I’ve completely sorted and catalogued all my LEGO.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/11/28/non-lego/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/11/28/non-lego/</guid>
        
        <category>non_lego</category>
        
        
        <category>general</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>LEGO Magazines</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Collecting sets is fine but to get fully immersed in the LEGO universe I think it makes sense to keep an eye on the news and information on LEGO as well. One traditional way for this is books and magazines. I recently subsribed to 2 magazines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/11/22/lego-magazines/IMG_3716.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blocks Magazine&lt;/strong&gt; seems to be more serious with lenghty articles and information. I subsrcibed for 2 years. Just the other day got the first 2 issues. I haven’t read them yet but just by looking through the content you can tell it’s targeting AFOLs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LEGO Explorer&lt;/strong&gt; This is a newer magazine and they have just released their Issue #2. They come with a small polybag and mostly have articles targeting a much younger audience. I think I’ll just give it a quick read and keep the polybags sealed and treat them as collectibles. Let’s see if they gain value over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also thinking about subscribing to the LEGO Star Wars magazine because of the polybags but the content is clearly for little chidlren I couldn’t justify it. Maybe later but for the time being I’ll focus on these two magazines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/11/22/lego-magazines/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/11/22/lego-magazines/</guid>
        
        <category>magazine</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Clearing Build Space</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been stressed out a bit lately as I bought all these sets and pieces but didn’t have any proper space to play. This was what I used to have:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/11/22/clearing-space/IMG_3496.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though it looked nice it didn’t give me enough play room. After moving the cabinets around the house now finally I have some space to fill with LEGO:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/11/22/clearing-space/IMG_3715.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let the building begin!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/11/22/clearing-build-space/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/11/22/clearing-build-space/</guid>
        
        <category>storage</category>
        
        <category>space</category>
        
        
        <category>build</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building Mindstorms Mini (40413)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In October and November I got a total of 8 Mindstorms Mini promo sets. I thought it’s a good time to build one to build up to the actual Mindstorms and SPIKE Prime sets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This set was surprisingly fun to build. Unlike the actual Mindstorms (51515) this is not a 5-in-1 model meaning you can build all 5 models at the same time with the pieces provided in the set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/11/15/mindstorms-mini/IMG_3704.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also comes a lot of extra pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/11/15/mindstorms-mini/IMG_3705.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the models even has an alternative build for the head:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/11/15/mindstorms-mini/IMG_3706.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up until the very end I was questioning if there would be enough pieces to build all these in set. Clearly there were and then some!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/11/15/building-mindstorms-mini-40413/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/11/15/building-mindstorms-mini-40413/</guid>
        
        <category>mindstorms</category>
        
        
        <category>build</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Star Wars Keychain Haul</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a post to document my recent purchases and some GWP (Gift with Purchase). Mainly I bought a bunch of stuff because of the Han Solo keychain promo over £100 Star Wars purchases. I also got 2 more Mindstorms Mini sets and 2 Hidden Side polybags. I was holding off Razor Crest and Death Star Final Duel but with these promos I couldn’t resist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/11/15/haul/IMG_3696.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to LEGO online order, I placed an order on eBay for an old Ideas set: Old Fishing Store (21310). I didn’t know it existed but instantly fell in love with the set and ordered. Its retail price was £140 and I paid £270 so nearly double. Hopefully it will be worth it after the build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/11/15/haul/IMG_3699.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another set I was planning to buy for some time is Snowtrooper Battle Pack (8084)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/11/15/haul/IMG_3700.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another interesting find is a LEGO book that comes with a few pieces and 2 minifigs. It’s called Hospital Heist by Scholastic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/11/15/haul/IMG_3701.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got a Star Wars sketch of First Order Stormtrooper as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/11/15/haul/IMG_3702.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally I don’t buy too much stuff from the sequels but this one is generic enough to pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also used some store credits and got these LEGO miscellanous sets for next to nothing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/11/15/haul/IMG_3703.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m planning to wait for deals from now on for quite a while before I buy more stuff but I figured these sets almost never go on sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s see how long I will be able to resist the urge!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/11/15/star-wars-keychain-haul/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/11/15/star-wars-keychain-haul/</guid>
        
        
        <category>haul</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Robot Inventor and SPIKE Prime First Tests</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last post, I published photos of my latest news which includes Robot Inventor (51515) and SPIKE Prime (45678). They are similar in the sense that they come with the same programmable brick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;spike-prime-and-expansion-set&quot;&gt;SPIKE Prime and Expansion Set&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought the expansion set because of this simple principle: In for a penny in for a pound! I had alerady spent too much money anyway so what’s another £110 between me and LEGO!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, it came with lots of pieces but only 1 sensor and 1 motor so probably wasn’t a great purchase after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/25/first-tests/spike-prime-motors-and-sensors.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you unbox SPIKE Prime, you don’t get a instruction booklet. There’s only a link that you’re supposed to visit to get started: &lt;a href=&quot;https://education.lego.com/en-gb/start&quot;&gt;LEGOEducation.com/start&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a step by step guide that shows you how to install the required software which is an iPadOS in my case called LEGO Education SPIKE. The app runs you through a tutorial thats shows how to build a program and deploy to the hub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before that it asked me to update Hub OS though which requires connecting the hub to a computer. It requires a software download on the computer to carry out the first update as the first update cannot be done via Bluetooth apparently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/25/first-tests/hub-os-update-01.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/25/first-tests/hub-os-update-02.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that I created a project and connected the motors and sensors and I was able to get some response and confirm they are working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;robot-inventor&quot;&gt;Robot Inventor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robot inventor set doesn’t come with paper instructions either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/25/first-tests/IMG_3658.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a similar set to SPIKE Prime but comes with different motors and sensors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the booklet, it suggested you go to this address to check your device: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lego.com/en-gb/service/device-guide&quot;&gt;LEGO.com/devicecheck&lt;/a&gt; which contains links to download the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I downloaded both iPadOS and macOS versions from the corresponding App Stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to SPIKE Prime, I connected the hub via USB and got this message:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/25/first-tests/mindstorms-new-project.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll try developing programs in Python later. Just to see everything is working fine I connected the motors and sensors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/25/first-tests/mindstorms-motors-and-sensors-connected.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found Bluetooth connection is a bit slow but it seems to work fine after it’s connected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having the ability to program in Python is great. It’s in beta mode now but I will give it a go anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I was able to see them in action, I will start building the robots that can be built by Robot Inventor and take it from there…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://antonsmindstorms.com/2020/10/17/lego-51515-robot-inventor-vs-spike-prime-set-45678/&quot;&gt;LEGO 51515 Robot Inventor vs. SPIKE Prime set 45678&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/10/25/robot-inventor-and-spike-prime-first-tests/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/10/25/robot-inventor-and-spike-prime-first-tests/</guid>
        
        <category>mindstorms</category>
        
        <category>spike_prime</category>
        
        <category>robot_inventor</category>
        
        
        <category>dev</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sith Troopers Mod Revisited</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month I published a small mod for my Sith Jet Troopers &lt;a href=&quot;https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/09/27/small-mod-for-sith-troopers-battlepack/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t really happy about the grey hinges as I was looking for something transparent. I came across &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bricklink.com/v2/catalog/catalogitem.page?P=65578#T=P&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a quick BrickLink order and updating the mod it looks a lot better now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/24/sith-mod/IMG_3646.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/24/sith-mod/IMG_3647.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/24/sith-mod/IMG_3648.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/24/sith-mod/IMG_3649.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moral of the story: Use right tools for the job and you’ll get better results.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/10/24/sith-troopers-mod-revisited/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/10/24/sith-troopers-mod-revisited/</guid>
        
        <category>double</category>
        
        <category>vip</category>
        
        <category>points</category>
        
        
        <category>haul</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Double VIP Point Haul</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The new LEGO Mindstorms set is finally out. Fortunately it also came with a nice promo (Mini Robots - 40413) which also happened during Double VIP Points rewards. So I went ahead and tried to take advantage of the promos:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/24/haul/IMG_3650.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/24/haul/IMG_3651.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/24/haul/IMG_3652.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/24/haul/IMG_3653.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next step is to get the Robot Inventor and SPIKE Prime open and test all electronics are working fine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 04:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/10/24/double-vip-point-haul/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/10/24/double-vip-point-haul/</guid>
        
        <category>double</category>
        
        <category>vip</category>
        
        <category>points</category>
        
        
        <category>haul</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sorting Bulk LEGO</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After realizing I was going to need lots and lots of pieces to build something with even medium size I started to buy bulk LEGO lots on eBay. In hindsight I now realize I overdid it! I bought about 160KG bulk LEGO and it took me ages to sort them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lessons-learned&quot;&gt;Lessons Learned&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You need to have a system. There are so many different bits and pieces it’s easy to get distracted and waste time on some low-value sorting actions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accept that even with a system it will take a LOOONG time!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure you have enough containers. I bought a whole bunch of Samla boxes from IKEA and they are extremely useful to me Also sorting trays help a lot for small parts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go in rounds. Don’t expect to sort every single piece at one go.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The smaller parts get the longer it takes to sort. So 80/20 rule is valid in this case as well. Initially you go very fast but you will still have to spend a lot more time when you get down to small items like minifigure hands, 1x1 plates, cheese slopes etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create broad categories for initial sorting and sub-sort later. It will be a lot easier to sort a big bucket of bricks, for example, among themselves later on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sorting-process&quot;&gt;Sorting Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After sorting 160KG bulk LEGO, I think I can formulate my (ideal) process as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;round-1&quot;&gt;Round #1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Large items (Baseplates, train tracks, large plates and bricks)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minifigures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Special / unique / vintage / fragile / valuable items&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Electric parts (Battery boxes, lights, sensors etc)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Half / full builds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Obvious Non-LEGO items&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;round-2&quot;&gt;Round #2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Separate the parts: Most bulk LEGO comes with lots of pieces attached to others. If I like a build and decide to keep it hoping that I will complete it in the future or just to identify the set, I keep it as is (as mentioned in round #1). Any other pieces attached together should be separated down to individual parts. In my experience it’s taking a long time just to separate these partial builds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;round-3&quot;&gt;Round #3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Separate the parts in these main categories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bricks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wheels / tires&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Doors / windows&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Foliage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wedges&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slopes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minifigures &amp;amp; accessories&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Windshields&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plates with clips and hinges&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Technic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unknown / unidentified (Looks and feels like LEGO but obscure parts)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Non-LEGO (You will find lots of off-brand bricks and lots of junk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did have more buckets than these when I sorted but I guess if I started over I would have done one full round on only these items. These take the majority of the entire bulk anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;round-4&quot;&gt;Round #4&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a Box4Blox and sort by size.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/20/sorting-bulk-lego/Box4Blox.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though this gadget is not very accurate it does help. I suggest do one round on the largest size. This way you always deal with similar sized items. Then go to middle tier and the smallest one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some before pictures:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/20/sorting-bulk-lego/IMG_3637.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/20/sorting-bulk-lego/IMG_3639.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And some after pictures:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/20/sorting-bulk-lego/IMG_3643.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/20/sorting-bulk-lego/IMG_3644.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know the after photos don’t look very impressive because I need to do some subsorting by element type as well and add to the inventory. But I’ll relax and do that over time. At least I was able to reclaim the space. It was getting quite depressing that my entire home was covered with bins and storage trays and I had no living space left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.box4blox.com/&quot;&gt;Box4Blox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 04:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/10/20/sorting-bulk-lego/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/10/20/sorting-bulk-lego/</guid>
        
        <category>bulk</category>
        
        
        <category>sorting</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Story So Far...</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I started Lego hobby some time before this blog. So before going further I wanted to publish a post just to document the sets I’ve built so far. Once I’m all caught up, I can move on with the new sets and mocs and such.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It all began with buying some Mindstorms sets back in 2007 but sadly I didn’t dedicate enough time to make something useful with those sets. That’s an issue I’m planning to address this time around.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Years after in 2014 I bought Mindstorms EV3. I built some robots with it but it wasn’t very satisfactory. Again will address that in the very near future.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After a few tries with Revell’s plastic models I decided to give Lego a go. That was an epiphany for me. I had all this Lego for developing robots, all the electronics (LEDs, Arduinos, Raspberry Pis). Everything I can combine with Lego to create great models.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As a test project to see if I would like Lego going forward I ordered Technic BASH!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/06/backlog/IMG_3623.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next up I paid a visit to Lego store in Leicester Square which is a fantastic place to visit:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/06/backlog/lego-big-ben.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/06/backlog/lego-mosaic.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Got my first set from the store: Creator Expert Harley-Davidson Fat Boy 10269&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/06/backlog/IMG_2425.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After that I started to order some smaller sets. Spending hundreds of pounds on Lego was inconceivable at that point. It’s funny how things changed in such a short period of time. Here are a few smaller sets I built and put on display after:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/06/backlog/IMG_2753.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/06/backlog/IMG_3263.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/06/backlog/IMG_3264.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/06/backlog/IMG_3624.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/06/backlog/IMG_3625.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/06/backlog/IMG_3626.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I also bought some keychains and started a small collection there too:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/06/backlog/IMG_3627.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At this point I realized that Lego sets almost never lose value which is why lots of people invest in Lego. Probably wasn’t great that I discovered this because I ended up with this:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/06/backlog/IMG_3260.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/06/backlog/IMG_3320.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m also interested in building my own MOCs. So I bought whole bunch of bulk Lego on eBay. Sorted some and my inventory system looks like this:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/06/backlog/IMG_3496.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I like the look of the inventory but when I tried to find which sets I can build using this inventory the results for quite disappointing. So I bought even more bulk Lego and currently in the process of sorting it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/10/06/backlog/sorting.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is clearly an ongoing process and I have LOTS of Lego to sort. I ordered more containers. In the next post I will discuss all different types of storage I use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly this is a very exhausting and time-consuming chore but it needs to be done before I can get serious about it. Now that I’m all caught up in this blog on my Lego journey I will try and post regularly about what comes next.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 04:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/10/06/the-story-so-far/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lego.volkanpaksoy.com/archive/2020/10/06/the-story-so-far/</guid>
        
        <category>backlog</category>
        
        
        <category>misc</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
